## **Ruslan Novikov**

Date of birth: 02.08.1975

Place of residence: Zhytomyr, Ukraine

Contact details: skype: Nofikoff

telegram: @Nofikoff

<u>ruslan.novikov@gmail.com</u> tel: +380 (93) 853-70-20

Accounts: https://github.com/nofikoff

https://linkedin.com/in/terminovo/

https://stackoverflow.com/users/1932494/



# Full Stack Developer / Chief Technology Officer (CTO)

## **Personal profile**

Full stack web developer seeking a full time remote position.

19 years programming experience, 11 years consulting experience.

Application of the accumulated experience in projects with a high level of responsibility. Intermediate level of English.

Highly motivated to continuously develop my skills and grow professionally.

# **Extensive expertise in**

- Team management, writing tech specifications, Agile, Scrum, Git, Version control.
- Teaching and coaching of computer science (PHP, JS, HTML/CSS, SEO, UI/UX)
- PHP, PHP Frameworks (Laravel, Yii2, Symfony), PHP CMS (WP, OpenCart, Bitrix, Drupal, MOD.
- JavaScript, Node.js
- Databases MySQL, MSSQL, Mongodb, Firebase
- Parsing/ Scrapping, RegExp
- SEO, PPC, E-mailing marketing
- Administration of Linux / Windows / MacOS, hosting, domains, Rest API, Docker

### **Proficient in**

- Golang, ReactJS, TypeScript, Vue, Angular, Android / iOS hybrid mobile apps.
- Memcached, Redis, Elasticsearch,
- ASP.NET Core, Razor, MVC.
- HTML / CSS (Bootstrap, Flex, Grid, SEO optimized layout), UI / UX, Landing pages.

## **Experience**

# 2020 November - to present Taxer.ua (tax filing service) CTO (remotely)

- o Formation of technical specifications
- o Angular frontend, component development
- o Laravel API backend, module development
- Interaction with developers, support
   Angular, Laravel, Amazon AWS, Typescript, Jira, MySQL, Vagrant, PHP

#### • 2014 – 2020 November

#### Freelance work

- o Development of parsers, aggregators, web databases, mobile applications.
- Search engine promotion and optimization.
- Customer training and consulting. https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCTC2frih1ReJV-e5sLkK9Zw/videos

#### 2000 - 2014

#### **Novikov Internet company (15** employees)

Founder and director of the company. Wide range of tasks:

- Recruitment and management of personnel
- Sales and customer service
- Full cycle of website and database development
- o Development and maintenance of websites
- o Software integration
- Staff training
- o Public webinars and seminars on SEO and E-commerce

About company <a href="https://novikov.ua/about/">https://novikov.ua/about/</a>

#### 1998 - 2000

Experience in several small commercial structures.

Wide range of responsibilities

- o Sales manager
- System Administrator
- Head of the first Internet incubator iNest (startup)

# Seminar and training program development (conducted more than 200 training events since 2005)

• Taking Control of Your Site's Search Engine Promotion. Digital Marketing: Ideas, Technologies and Business Opportunities.

https://novikov.ua/seminars/promo/

- Secrets of a Successful Online Store: Success Factors and Common Mistakes https://novikov.ua/seminars/portal-development/
- Personal Cyber Security: Cyber Threats in Everyday Life https://novikov.ua/seminars/cyber-security/

## Business processes, management and sales

- Extensive experience in recruitment, interviewing, training and managing employees (15 people): programmers, designers, digital marketers, managers, content creators
- Experience in Sales and Negotiating. Drafting of contracts, including international contracts
- Development of complex technical tasks for Internet databases and Web applications. Subsequent
  control of implementation. Examples of industries: government procurement portal, accounting for
  merchandisers, land registry for GOK, electronic document management of legal enterprises, billing
  system for hosting and domains with automatic payment using various payment gateways, Internet
  Stores.
- **My online store** <a href="https://Terminovo.ua">https://Terminovo.ua</a> Management of warehouse, couriers, sales managers and remote team. Telephone sales and online chat support.
- Small business owner for automatic domain registration and hosting sales
   <u>https://Pogonyalo.com</u>
   . Billing panel integrated with payment systems and hosting. Ticket system support.

## **Education**

1998 graduated from the National Technical University of Ukraine.

Master's degree in Computer Science, Complexes, Systems and Networks

### Reference

Lyubov Tribun Regional Manager "IT STEP" Zhytomyr

Phone: +38 097 949 90 17 Email: tribun-lyubasha@ukr.net